so just be careful with Charity okay
particularly at
Christmas that's when they sting you and
they give you a guilt trip you're
sitting down Christmas day you got all
your food loads of food too much food
probably going to throw a lot of it away
and all the adverts onia for charity
right um this one runs every Christmas
day is there an old lady near you cold
and lonely this Christmas yep a [__]
hater nosy [__] windes me up all year
I can't wait for the cold weather if I'm
being
honest there's no old lady near me she
died last year of hypothermia so result
the other big campaign the other big
campaign a dog is for life not just for
Christmas right behind that I love
animals I'm really into animal welfare
and that's obviously aimed at parents
whose kids go can I have a puppy can I
have a puppy no can I have a puppy can I
and they give in to shut them up and
they get the puppy and they like it when
it's cute then they grow up and they get
bored with it and they love with the
parents with it and the parents get
bored with it and they abandon it 11,000
pets abandon in England Wales last year
and I think kids should have pets I
think it teaches them life lessons I
haven't got children of my own but I've
got loads of nieces and nephews and
they've got kids of their own now and I
want to be a cool uncle and give them
what they want but I want to be a
responsible one too and sort of not add
to the Stray problem but I think I've
solved the Dilemma this is what I do
okay as a tip you got to wait till
Christmas Eve go to an animal shouter or
an animal rescue home not a breeder and
I go there and and I go straight to the
veterinary bit and when they're dealing
with like the little runts that are born
all sick and they're just putting them
down they got no quality of life I go no
don't kill that one I'll take that one
and they go it's only going to live a
day so I run home with it going don't
die yet get your Starbucks a little bit
of Starbucks don't die yet don't die and
I run in and I call my niece she runs up
go look oh you got a puppy I your best
uncle got you a puppy oh thanks go and
play with quick go and play with
it and they take it to bed Christmas Eve
and they sleep with it and they wake up
Christmas day it's cold dead stiff gone
so not a problem um and they always come
down they
say my pupp is dead and I go what the
puppy your uncle got you he did his bit
and whatever happened after that isn't
his problem and they go yeah and I go oh
no maybe you rolled over on it on the
night oh did I oh no
and they was go I killed my puppy I
killed my puppy I go no no you didn't
kill your puppy Jesus killed your
puppy on his birthday cuz you didn't
spend enough on your uncle's Christmas
present so they usually Buck their ideas
up the next year um the other big
campaign of course don't drink and drive
right behind that as well a lot more
stigma attached now um when I was
growing up there was no Stigma it was
like if you got away with it that was
all right I I'd be getting in the car
with grown-ups and family and I'd go oh
you can't drive you're drunk and they go
it's all right I won't get caught but
people now know that that's not the
point it wrecks lives I've done it once
I'm not proud of it in the slightest I'm
[__] ashamed of it I wasn't drunk but
I was over the limit that was Christmas
and I took the car out and I knew I
shouldn't I knew at the time I shouldn't
be in this car but I learned my lesson
cuz I nearly killed an old woman in the
end I didn't kill her in the end I just
raped her
but as I say nothing came of it cuz
luckily thousand to one shot I know she
had
Alzheimer's yeah not a credible witness
I tell you what spiders they're always
ready aren't they spiders always ready
for action a spider is always ready like
that completely ready all the time I
mean some animals are sometimes ready
you scare a cat and go o like that okay
then it goes back to chill they most of
the time they're just on on their side
aren't they cats cats are just chill out
that head down all four limbs stretched
out in One Direction you will never see
a spider like that you will never see a
spider just lying on the floor with his
head down like that and all eight legs
just out like
that what what the [__] they're always
ready like that and they're always ready
in every direction like the [__]
Matrix they don't have to go what was
that they don't have to do it they got
[__] 10 eyes and eight legs over the
top they're even ready when you don't
think they're ready you can see an empty
web you go that spider's not ready no
touch the web what touch the web and
it's
there I [__] hate
them
37,000 different species of spider
37,000 different species of spider I
mean millions and billions of individual
in each species okay and that's just one
class arachnid of one philm arthropoda
which there are many there could be 5
million species of animal on the earth
best guess right minimum scientists say
there's so many we can't but 5 million
and that's 1% of all animal species that
have ever existed 99% of all animal
species that ever existed are extinct
and that remaining 1% is 5 million
strong take one of those species
termites if you were to weigh every
termite alive now it would be 10 times
the tonnage of every human being on
Earth and it's statistics like that that
make me think that this book isn't
totally accurate um
it's the uh the book of Noah um the
children's Edition um I got this as a
prize at Sunday school I used to go
every week I believed in all this till I
was about eight um this is when I was
four um St Agnes Sunday school presented
to Ricky ja r i Ki like a [__]
mongus for regular attendance not even
for doing anything good just for turning
up
oh he's always there give him some it'll
be back thank
you let's have a look at the
evidence long long ago when God first
made the Earth I'll let both those
points slip we haven't got time okay
long long ago I should just say um is
5,000 years according to the Bible
according to the Old Testament the Earth
is no older than 5,000 years okay which
puts us around the time of the
Agricultural Revolution uh it's it's
actually 4.6 billion years old let's pop
that
in 4.6 billion years ago when God first
made the Earth and Sky all right don't
big it up I mean it it comes as a
package really doesn't it you couldn't
the sky was never an optional extra it
could be built your planet I can't
breathe would you like an atmosphere of
course I [__] would
so everything was peaceful everything
beautiful God made made human beings too
and he wanted them to be good like
himself
arrogant but very soon they wanted their
own way they would not listen to God
they became Wicked and did Wicked things
look at them doing wicked things there
look at that you can't get more wicked
than that R oh [__] off
Wicked R [__] off
Wicked God looking on yeah carry on see
what happens see what
happens bloke there running off with a
big bag of money
don't put it in a bank you
[__] this lecture as you've worked out
is about political change no but how do
you change things if you want to change
S how do you change things well we're
not all in power by definition some of
us haven't even got the vote but if
you've got a voice in our country we got
freedom of speech you can change things
slowly but you can be heard and that
that's one way and I used to work at
University of London Union and there
wasn't a day went by when there wasn't a
March that started outside or people
giving out flyers and leaflets and stuff
and I always used to take them to read
them CU I wanted to know what people
were giving up their time for and I
remember one um was a a leaflet
boycotting Nike and some other designer
labels for using third world sweat shops
particularly China and there was a
frightening statistic on this leaflet I
never forget it said that the CEO of
Nike has amassed $5.2
billion and for a female worker in one
of his sweat shops in in China to earn
that she'd have to work 7 days a week 8
hours a day for 10,000 years but they
don't want
to
Lazy there was another thing on there
it's absolutely true um one of the
supervisors in one of the sweat shops in
China I've been accused of sexually
assaulting one of the female workers
and um he'd been um that's not funny is
it no Dre and um he was suspended but
fled the country before he come to trial
and the CEO of Nike was asked an awkward
question about this at a press
conference and he said no he wasn't
sexually assaulting her he was trying to
wake her up and must have touched the
wrong
places what that's a bad excuse isn't it
touch
what Mrs is
CH this is
CH just shout don't touch her at
all Mrs
CH but I love bad excuses when they're
sort of embarrassing sort of heinous
things like that I remember a friend of
mine I went to college with was a
medical student and when he did his
degree uh he did a um an internship or
Junior doctor at University College
Hospital and uh he was working at nights
it was about 1:30 in the morning and
this guy came in and he had a bottle of
sauce stuck up his
ass as you do and uh completely
disappeared he hadn't left like you know
enough out he hadn't thought of the
return
Journey but even Hans and gret sort left
breadcrumbs didn't I he hadn't he hadn't
thought it through he was getting so
into it the whole bottle up there oh
then he couldn't get any purchase he
couldn't you know tie a bit of string to
it or something just think ahead or
empty it out fill it with concrete put a
broom handle in it let that set then
you've got the full length of the bottle
and a
handle but he hadn't he hadn't put as
much thought into it as me
um amateur now
so and also instead of going in there
and saying excuse me mate um got a sauce
bottle stuck at my
ass I know what I was doing you know
what I was doing uh get it out and I
won't do it again instead of saying that
he went through his whole face saving
rigal of filling out an accident report
just just making it worse for himself
and this is the excuse he gave okay he
said well what what happened was this is
a great excuse Right Said
I'd been shopping at
Safeway um and I came home with my
shopping and I realized that I'd locked
myself out of my house so I put the
shoing on the
doorstep and I saw that I left open a
bedroom window so I thought I'll get in
there so I tried to climb up the drain
pipe but as as I was climbing the the
drain pipe um my belt broke um and my
trousers and
pants fell down I I I went to I lost my
grip and I fell and I landed on the
bottle that went stra and that's that's
what
happened okay so got it out for him when
he uh when he left they made an
amendment to the accident report my mate
put this story would be somewhat more
believable if Safeway sold their bottles
of sauce with condoms already
attached just the oh the condom
[__] he knows I'm lying why did he put a
condom on anyway
cuz he was then going to use it on his
chips but how mean is that if you're
into you know what I mean shoving
condiments up your ass buy two they're
only
79p I guess I don't know I'm
not one for chips one for asses you know
where you are you have to make bad
excuses
[Applause]
my um my favorite leaflet of all time I
bet some of you haven't even got a
favorite leaflet have you sort it out um
no really it really is um you'll see why
and I kept it with me for about 3 months
and showed to everyone it was a leaflet
that came around the union um in about
1994 995 and it was a Terrence Higgins
um leaflet about um safe sex and it was
aimed at the last demographic of of game
men that weren't taking HIV seriously
enough and so it was very hard-hitting
and seen and it used like really sort of
colorful language to get the message
class and I remember it so well and uh
the title of this fly you know it's
going to be a good leaflet when this is
the title this is the opening Gambit
right it was
called you know you don't always have to
have anal
sex thanks very
much think of a couple of old age
pensioners just queuing for their flu JB
they're just browsing we just digest
what's this
one you know you don't always have to
have anal sex see I [__] told
you so that was what it's called right
and it was a 10-point plan of
alternatives to you know that so number
one okay always started the same as well
always started with why not right why
not like casual like saying like um like
a recipe or something why not throw in
an onion
right right okay number one was this and
it had those little diagrams like little
drawings like you get on safety things
on planes so anyway number one 10-point
plan number one
was think of this as medical advice okay
number one was why not just wank each
other
off I got the new leaflet oh what does
it say why don't SW each other off okay
oh casual number
two number two was great again just a
casual suggestion right number two
was what always the same why not number
two why not come on his back
why
not when is that this so why not imagine
you queue up to see a GP they go the GP
see you now and he's sort of writing
come in s what can I do for you um I'm
I'm gay and I'm worried about HIV
um come on his
back number three whenever I showed this
to people when I got to this one people
were laughing going oh and they went oh
right number three it's the worst one
number three
is why not come in his
hair not the
hair on the
back come on the back sure I you go go
on but that's where my fascination with
animals started at school and I did I
did well at school but I I thought that
I just learn to pass exams as opposed to
I feel like I just want to get so much
knowledge now it must be a sign of age
but I just I want to know about
everything things I never cared about
before I've got digital TV and there 72
channels all [__] except I watch hours
and end of the History Channel and
Discovery Channel now just back and
forth like 6 hours stin History Channel
Discovery Channel back and forth ask me
anything about sharks and
Nazis not as bad as a lot of people make
out um sharks I mean NIS horrible oh
don't sharks brilliant Nazis rubbish but
the Sharks an amazing creature it's got
sense up its body it can tell the
slightest movement in water of a
floundering fish through electrical
impulse it can Zone in on that um it's
got good eyesight cont to popular belief
and it can taste and smell the slightest
human secretion of like blood and sweat
one part in a billion from a mile away a
shark would have found an Frank like
that Nazis rubbish
no no time for them no time for them um
I've been to a house it's tiny I can't
believe one of them didn't go let's look
upstairs today you know what I
mean what the [__] were they doing okay
yes sge sge wait what what's that
tapping
noise rats move
on she had time to write a novel for
Christ's sake well it ends a bit
abruptly no sequel lazy um
no I'm not here not here to talk about
war and but particular this time you
know and uh we're to uh not my favorite
war over the second world war you know
well if you're asking the
folklands people say it was a conflict
it was a war um and it was uh it's my
favorite war because it was a range War
what that means is that uh the ARG guns
could fire 9 km and our guns could fire
17 so we just parked our boats about 10
km
and they were falling into the sea and
we were shelling the [__] out of them
it's it's the war equivalent of holding
a [__] at arms
length and he's
fllying and you're just steadily kicking
in the
bollocks what's it called Mal Venus
crap what's it called um that's why the
Falon is my favorite war a little mget
fellow
uh Vietnam best soundtrack
definitely first world war was good you
know they say it was a great War it
wasn't great it was good I mean no I
mean it wasn't wasn't great for me the
great has got to be perfect it wasn't
per I like the bayonets and the master
gas like the Poetry that oh that sort of
brought do you know what I mean brings a
war down for me poetry o it's the only
time poetry isn't bent but even so let's
keep it out of War you know what I mean
there's one poem everyone goes on about
CU it's very poignant because the the
soldier uh died writing it and uh I
suppose it is quite po it's called we
are the dead it goes we are the dead
once we lived felt the sun in our face
loved and were loved and now we lie in
flanders's fields be honest if You' had
a gun in your hand instead of a pen
mate what are you
doing what the [__] put it down pick
your gun up your C
look uh
let's have a game of football in no
man's
land
um second world war was all right but
not uh the ending that oh that tears a
lot of people Cu uh we say all you know
the abomb it's you know Atomic power's
bad but war is bad but it ended a war so
you know and it was invented by Einstein
essentially uh Atomic um Power and he's
brilliant and he so so bright
um no he he said that uh light could be
described as discret bundles of energies
that when a radiated onto an un what s
[__] thinks like that do you know
me that's what turned step arkins mental
too much
thinking I I'm not a doctor but I'm
pretty sure it's too much too too much
swatting can send you a little bit like
him I I don't know but it's not like the
universe is expanding of course it is
Steven now take a dial go for a walk not
a walk but I mean go out no just open a
window at least just cut watch a bit of
Telly robot wars is on you like that but
just I'm just I don't I'm not oh don't
ever go with Steven Orin he's a gen he's
not genius he's
pretentious born in Kent and talks in
the American accent
[Applause]
I'm oh no more war no more war on AR
things animals have been used in war
traditionally for you know forever I
mean Cavalry and they used to send in
dogs and goats to rip up the hores
underbelly in the 10th century and stuff
and I was looking on the um US Navy
website researching the show and uh
looking at the person now and they've
got in the US Marines it's absolutely
true they've got a 90 strong team of um
sea lions and dolphins and they're
trained to take these depth charges down
and drop them under submarines and blow
the I mean they don't know what they're
doing they don't for a bit of fish but
it's still but I think mainly it's the
dolphins that do all the dangerous stuff
and the Sea lines are more for morale
when they get back going that was
brilliant well done let's go to what you
going to do tomorrow's I I would I think
I've got a bit hooping cough coming on
So you you're doing a brilliant job
um uh I did a lot of research on the
internet for this uh lecture and um it
is the greatest resource in the world
but it's sort of clogged up with people
doing homemade websites about themselves
I it's stuff like my name is ruper this
is my cat thanks very much uh here are
my favorite Cure songs in order I don't
give a why you and there's trivia
websites where people sort of go on
there and add to them something they
have to share with the world that they
think we care and uh they credit
themselves they must wake up in a cold
sweat and go oh I must tell the world
this and this is a real one um the
peanut is not a nut it is a legum few
and I want to share with you some of my
favorite ones this is a um from Debon
Jen's world of trivia it's it's a real
website that everyone goes on to and uh
page three of 84 huh my my favorite the
animal facts of course now some of these
are true some of them are a little bit
embellished some I'm not sure about but
always think of the person who's telling
us this why is telling the world this
what is his motivation what what's he
thinking right
okay there we go you can lead a cow
upstairs but not
down that's true by the way it's it's
the way they're they joints don't oppose
so a cow will go upstairs but it won't
go think of the poor bastard who found
that out the hard way um
but they come on Daisy down you go oh I
can't go downstairs me joints I don't
care about your joints my wife's coming
home in 5 minutes get down the
stairs fcking
stairs um have you seen those blowup
cows and blowup sheep you can get in an
Summers and sex shops I I now the point
of a blowup doll is presumably for a man
who can't get a real woman how [__] I
if you can't get a real
sheep for